<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: language | Cluckings of Kate]]></title>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/categories/language/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-08T12:43:09+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kate Chapman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Words, Words, Words, Everywhere]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2012/01/26/words-words-words-everywhere/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-26T09:35:17+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2012/01/26/words-words-words-everywhere</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my travels in Indonesia I’ll hear a word and then notice it is being used all the time in conversation.  Sometimes this is in a particular type of conversations other times it is not. I usually look them up right then or ask someone later when it is an appropriate time. Sometimes however they can’t understand what I’m asking them. In this case it takes much longer to find out what they mean.</p>

<p>One of those words was “merica.” Initially I asked <a href="http://whateverisaid.wordpress.com/">Emir Hartato</a> what it meant, but I must not have said it correctly. He didn’t understand what I mean.  So next I tried looking it up but I thought it was spelled “merica.” Looking this up though the word meant “pepper,” I knew this wasn’t right.  So either there was an additional meaning Google Translate wasn’t giving me or I had spelled the word wrong.  This word was being used a lot in meetings so I was sure they weren’t talking about pepper!</p>

<p>So after wondering about this for a long time the word appeared again in yesterday’s training class.  The discussion was about what we were going to do tomorrow, but I still wasn’t sure what the word meant.  Then I stumbled across it on a sign in the restaurant in our hotel!  Mystery solved I was spelling it wrong!  The actual word was “mereka” which can mean “to plan” or as a pronoun “they.” This word completely makes sense in the context of what people were talking about.</p>

<p><a href="http://wonderchook.com/wp-content/uploads/wonderchook.com/2012/01/mereka.png"><img src="http://wonderchook.com/wp-content/uploads/wonderchook.com/2012/01/mereka.png" alt="The sign that said it all" /></a></p>

<p>Maybe someday I’ll understand enough surrounding words that I’ll be able to figure out more vocabulary without these crazy adventures! I think I pick up 2 or 3 words a day naturally, maybe more.  It is hard to count though, since sometimes I learn words without realizing it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
