<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: workplace | Cluckings of Kate]]></title>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/categories/workplace/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-08T12:43:09+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kate Chapman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The #pwyw Experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/pay-what-you-want-for-peer-help/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-21T04:14:03+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/pay-what-you-want-for-peer-help</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So previously I've read about restaurants switching to models of "pay what you want." For example <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/05/21/us/21free.html">Panera Bread tried that model in 2010 in Missouri</a>. Checking back in 2011 it <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/2011-05-16-panera-pay-what-you-can_n.htm">appears to still be going strong</a>. Though the model hasn't worked when applied to a Panera Bread in Portland, Oregon.  There <a href="http://consumerist.com/2011/09/why-paneras-pay-what-you-can-restaurant-didnt-work-in-portland.html">people ended up not paying, but also staying in the restaurant for many hours</a>. <a href="http://marginalrevolution.com/">Tyler Cowen</a> an economics professor <a href="http://www.salon.com/2010/06/17/pay_what_you_can_restaurants/">suggests that this method is unlikely to work for very many restaurant, especially if the method ceases to be a novelty</a>.</p>

<h2>Can This Model Work for Peer to Peer Consulting?</h2>

<p>I would like to experiment with this model for peer to peer consulting. I've considered this for sometime, but in the past I have no had enough control over my time to really try it. Technologists often help each other out, be it through online forums, twitter, direct communication or through publishing knowledge to blogs or source-code repositories. There are sometimes those problems though that are too complex or too specific perhaps to depend on these methods.</p>

<p>There have been times where I have been stuck on a problem and would have been overjoyed to have someone with expertise in that subject be able to sit down for a hour and help.  In these cases sometimes I felt it was asking too much for someone to assist with what I was stuck. Also there have been cases in the past where people maybe wanted me to teach them something and either time didn't allow or they were afraid to ask. This experiment is an attempt to eliminate this embarrassment.</p>

<h2>The Experiment</h2>

<ol>
<li><p>I will publish office hours a week in advance</p></li>
<li><p>You can go sign-up for slots, including a description and how I will contact you. I'm open to any means of communication as long as they are free.</p></li>
<li><p>At the slotted time we will begin working on your problem. If it is a problem where it is be worked on asynchronously then I will work on it during the time-slot. If it is something that more requires discussion it will occur during the reserved time.</p></li>
<li><p>If you are satisfied with the help and would like to pay for it then you can pay me through Paypal, send me a gift, trade anything that seems appropriate to you.</p></li>
</ol>


<h2>Are You Not Going to Help Informally Anymore?</h2>

<p>No don't worry about that. Nothing is going to change in my interactions within the <a href="http://openstreetmap.org">OpenStreetMap</a> Community, the <a href="http://hot.openstreetmap.org/">Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team</a>, <a href="http://crisismappers.net/">CrisisMappers</a> or any other place that I am active. This is simply a new method to get my assistance.</p>

<h2>What Might Topics Can You Help?</h2>

<p>I am the type of person that has varied interests, so I have held many types of jobs in the arena of mapping for the past ten years. Below are some items I am qualified for assisting.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Geographic Data Analysis</p></li>
<li><p>Introduction to Programming in Ruby or JavaScript</p></li>
<li><p>Learning How to Get Started with OpenStreetMap</p></li>
<li><p>Basics of using a Linux/Unix based operating system</p></li>
<li><p>Using OpenStreetMap for humanitarian purposes</p></li>
<li><p>Setting Up a Non-profit Organization (basic process in DC)</p></li>
<li><p>Creating Presentations</p></li>
<li><p>Social Media Usage (I only put this for the people that really, really don't get Twitter. But you probably aren't reading my blog if that is the case)</p></li>
<li><p>Creating Data Collection Strategies</p></li>
<li><p>Writing Software Requirements</p></li>
<li><p>Creating a Technical Resume</p></li>
<li><p>Online Technical Community Management</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Maybe you know me well and there is a topic I don't even know someone would want my expertise.</p>

<h2>How to Try It</h2>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://www.google.com/calendar/selfsched?sstoken=UUNpSnV1b2VNVWQ4fGRlZmF1bHR8M2Q1YTQ4MWI5OWQzZTVlZjA4NzRjNjYzZDAyZmNmYTc">appointment slots available in my calendar</a> (you may have to sign in with Google, if there is a better solution please let me know in the comments). Please don't forget to include a description of why you are making the appointment and how you would like me to contact you.</p>

<p>So it begins, I'll be Tweeting about my experiences with this under #pwyw,if you use this service or start your own you should too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Find a Man Someday]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2011/12/03/sexism-in-a-womens-work-group/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-03T16:33:42+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2011/12/03/sexism-in-a-womens-work-group</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I was reminded the other day of a story from back when I worked at ChoicePoint. Like most places ChoicePoint had its problems, but was an okay place to work most of the time.  Then it was a company of 5,000 people and everyone really ended up in there own little work cliques based on interests or job function.  My clique at work as mostly comprised of the technical people that worked on iMapData and/or those that played sports.  The gender was pretty well mixed there.  I usually judge that at a company by how often when I'm in a meeting of 5-10 people that I'm the only woman in the room.  It was very rare there.</p>

<p>There were different groups you could participate in that were part of the vision of becoming rated one of the best places to work.  One of these was a women's professional group (the actual name is escaping me at the moment).  Honestly I only began going to the group because they provided lunch and I wanted to see who else went.  Most of the women there were from different functions within the company, most where not technical.  I kept attending, because I thought it was good to meet people who worked in other areas and the speakers were interesting sometimes.  There was one incident where I decided not to anymore though.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carol_A._DiBattiste">Carol DiBattiste</a> who was the Chief Privacy Officer at the time was speaking, I was interesting in seeing what she had to say. Carol had an interesting career before ChoicePoint, including serving United States Under Secretary of the Air Force and Deputy Administrator of the TSA.  This talk occurred at least five years ago and I'm fuzzy on most of the details, but I was intrigued to listen to her talk about the decisions she had made and the people she had as bosses.  What I remember most about the talk though is one of the women asked Carol DiBattiste if she was married, she replied something along the lines of "no, that hasn't happened in my life yet."  I didn't think too much of this at that moment, but what happened at the end of the talk made me think about it.</p>

<p>After the session had broken up and people began to leave I was walking behind two women that worked as administrative assistants.  They were talking about what they had heard, but mostly it was about Carol not being married.  The conversation went like this, "It must be hard for her to find a man who is more successful than her" and then the other woman replied, "Well, she shouldn't worry. She'll find a man someday."  It seemed to me that all that these ladies had gotten out of the talk was that being successful would make it hard to get married.  Nothing about the interesting experiences and opportunities it allows.</p>

<p>After that I never returned to the women's group.  As someone who normally spent time with the technologists and geeks both at work and socially I didn't have that much in common with them. Still to this day I am reminded of that women's group when the topic of sexism in the workplace comes up.  I can't say that this was the most sexist thing I heard or experienced during my employment at ChoicePoint.  There were more of the typical incidents as well, such as when I found an interesting exploit in our web application.  The response from one of the men I showed it to was, "did you husband do that?"  Though I don't think about that as much, I think more about I wonder what became of those two women.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
