<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: indonesia | Kate Chapman]]></title>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.com/blog/categories/indonesia/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-08T13:35:42+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://wonderchook.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kate Chapman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Words, Words, Words, Everywhere]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.com/blog/2012/01/26/words-words-words-everywhere/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-26T09:35:17+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.com/blog/2012/01/26/words-words-words-everywhere</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my travels in Indonesia I’ll hear a word and then notice it is being used all the time in conversation.  Sometimes this is in a particular type of conversations other times it is not. I usually look them up right then or ask someone later when it is an appropriate time. Sometimes however they can’t understand what I’m asking them. In this case it takes much longer to find out what they mean.</p>

<p>One of those words was “merica.” Initially I asked <a href="http://whateverisaid.wordpress.com/">Emir Hartato</a> what it meant, but I must not have said it correctly. He didn’t understand what I mean.  So next I tried looking it up but I thought it was spelled “merica.” Looking this up though the word meant “pepper,” I knew this wasn’t right.  So either there was an additional meaning Google Translate wasn’t giving me or I had spelled the word wrong.  This word was being used a lot in meetings so I was sure they weren’t talking about pepper!</p>

<p>So after wondering about this for a long time the word appeared again in yesterday’s training class.  The discussion was about what we were going to do tomorrow, but I still wasn’t sure what the word meant.  Then I stumbled across it on a sign in the restaurant in our hotel!  Mystery solved I was spelling it wrong!  The actual word was “mereka” which can mean “to plan” or as a pronoun “they.” This word completely makes sense in the context of what people were talking about.</p>

<p><a href="../images/mereka.png"><img src="../images/mereka.png" alt="The sign that said it all" /></a></p>

<p>Maybe someday I’ll understand enough surrounding words that I’ll be able to figure out more vocabulary without these crazy adventures! I think I pick up 2 or 3 words a day naturally, maybe more.  It is hard to count though, since sometimes I learn words without realizing it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Indonesian]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.com/blog/2011/12/18/learning-indonesian/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-18T15:37:56+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.com/blog/2011/12/18/learning-indonesian</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As many of you know I've spent the past year traveling in and out of Indonesia.  I've never previously spent as much time in one country other than the United States. It has been a new experience for me learning a language mostly through immersion.  I say "mostly" because I do have a book I study sometimes and I also quiz people when I have questions.  Though maybe quizzing people is part of immersion, I'm not sure if there are rules...</p>

<p>About a month ago something clicked in my learning.  I started to understand a lot more.  This happened immediately after returning from a trip to Switzerland, not randomly one day while I was in Indonesia.  While in Switzerland I was in Geneva and in Bern.  I began taking German when I was in 8th grade and also studied it in College.  So while in Bern I was able to understand much of what people were saying.  I haven't used my German in years so speaking it did not work very well, but I could understand.  Coming back though I was extremely surprised to be understanding a lot more Indonesian the first day I was back.</p>

<p>I'm unsure if using my second language unlocked something in using another one.  For me it seems to have. I've begun picking up words at a much faster rate for example and entire sentences will make sense to me instead of previously when I would think "oh wait, I understand that word and that one, but...hmmmm I have no idea what is going on." One thing I haven't begun picking up too much of though yet is grammer.  I think that is something I'm just going to have to be better about studying.</p>

<p>Though this new found understanding has lead to one new goal for me personally though.  Not to zone out when people are speaking in Indonesian.  It is easy to do, because listening where you don't understand everything can be exhausting.  However I'm making a real effort to pay attention the whole time.  Something I don't know if I would have had the brain capacity to do before when I had no idea what was going on.</p>

<p>We'll see what happens the next time I return, I'm heading back to the US for the holidays and will try to keep up on my studying when I am there.  If you are curious as to the book I've been learning from it is called "<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Instant-Indonesian-express-different-Phrasebook/dp/0804833710">Instant Indonesian</a>" and it focuses on specific words and phrases you would use in everyday conversation.  I suspect I will need a new book in a couple months, but it has been really helpful to me so far.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
