<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: dc | Cluckings of Kate]]></title>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/categories/dc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-08T12:43:09+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kate Chapman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Secret....We Talk About You]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2011/12/05/little-secret-we-talk-about-you/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-05T12:14:18+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2011/12/05/little-secret-we-talk-about-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>_For some of you that have recently moved to DC you will roll your eyes. Mostly because this joke of mine is a bit old. _</p>

<p>So I have lived in the Washington, D.C. area for the past 20 years. For those of you doing the math (well who also know my age) that means since I was 12 years old or since the beginning of 7th grade. I grew up in Herndon, Virginia, went to Oakton High School in Vienna and studied Geography at George Mason University. Frequently when people are moving to DC they ask me about it, how I like the city, what sort of communities there are, downsides, etc. My response more often than not is "I'll let you in on a little secret, we talk about you." The response is usually "huh?" or "what?" I then go on to explain, "well those of us that have been here for a while are in it for the long haul."</p>

<p>What does this mean? In DC there are many people who have moved for their careers. DC is a short stop for them, to work on the Hill, to work for a big organization like the World Bank or to make money in contracting for the U.S. government. Many of these people aren't invested in making DC a home. I love the different communities in DC, especially the different art and tech ones. Sometimes it is difficult to decide what to do on any day of the week. To me DC is a great place to be a geek.</p>

<p>My advice to people moving it look for those specific niche groups that share the same interests as you. If one doesn't exist start one. Need help finding one here are a couple of my favorites. Since I travel so much now you won't often see me at one of them myself, but if any of them sound interesting go check them out.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://mowity.com/">MoWiTy</a> or Monkeys with Typewriters is one of my favorite events I almost never get to attend. It began during National Novel Writing Month (NaNoWriMo) last year, after November people didn't want the weekly write-ins to end. That was how MoWiTy came to be. An informal writing group people get together once a week to work on projects. Writing has a very loose definition, meaning you don't have to be working on a novel to join. Some write code, some draw cartoons, I usually blog and of course there are those working on novels. Sound interesting? Join the mailing list to keep up on where/when the next MoWity is.</p></li>
<li><p>For those friends of the geonerd persuasion there is <a href="http://www.meetup.com/GeoNerds-DC/">Geonerds DC</a>. This year after <a href="http://www.wherecampdc.org/">WhereCampDC</a> there was a desire to continue to get together more regularly. Previous there had been a similar group GeoDC, but the organizers (myself and Robert Soden) got busy and stopped scheduling it. So if you are interesting in web maps, GIS or any other kind of geospatial this is the place to be.</p></li>
<li><p>If you are specifically interested in OpenStreetMap there is a seperate group for that as well called <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/mappingdc?hl=en">MappingDC</a>. Events are organized as people have the desire and the best way to find out the next one is join the mailing list. Or if there is somewhere that you want to map and have people come and help out, then host a Mapping Party yourself.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.superartfight.com/">Super Art Fight</a> isn't a DC specific phenomena. Though there are events in DC that I suggest you check out. Artists are given large canvases and sharpies, then a wheel is spun to determine topics. At the end of a round the audience votes on who the winner is. In additional to the actual drawing their is live commentary and unexpected changes in topics. A mix between graffiti and stand-up comedy it is worth trying out.</p></li>
<li><p>I've participating in a lot of Ignites around the world, both as a presenter and audience member. <a href="http://ignite-dc.com/">Ignite-DC</a> is the Washington, DC version of this. DC has so many different types of interesting people and speakers so the quality at Ignite-DC is always great. This is also a great way to find out about things going on in DC and what people are doing that you might not hear about otherwise.</p></li>
<li><p>One meet-up that has a special place for me is <a href="http://www.accessibilitydc.org/">Accessibility DC</a>. A monthly meet-up it is focused on making technology accessible for all. Ever wondered how it is for someone to use a screenreader to view your website? Why is captioning so important? For me AccessDC has taught me to think differently about how technology can be used and applied to people's daily lives. Everyone has the same wants and desires for information, how can we make that a reality?</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joined GeekEasy]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2011/11/12/joined-geekeasy/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-12T05:59:09+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2011/11/12/joined-geekeasy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi should have probably posted this before I left DC, since the next-time I'll be able to use it is early 2012.  I joined as a drop <a href="http://www.geekeasy.org/">GeekEasy</a>, GeekEasy is a new coworking space in NW DC near the corner of 14th and Florida.</p>

<p>For those that aren't familiar with the idea, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coworking">coworking</a> is getting together somewhere with likeminded people.  This is to simulate an office working environment.  Or at least the parts of it you miss when you work remotely all the time.  There are different types of facilities, some are generic, some focused around start-ups, some focused at technical people, others aimed at social enterprise.  GeekEasy is specifically aimed at geeks, my life-long friend <a href="http://xiann.com/">Christiann</a> was the first to join and that is what got me over there.  She and I work together in other locations, but sometimes a change of scenery can be really helpful.</p>

<p>Anyway, if you are in DC and need somewhere to go and work you should check it out.  Maybe I'll see you there sometime in 2012!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
