<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: kate's brain | Cluckings of Kate]]></title>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/categories/kate-s-brain/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-08T12:43:09+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kate Chapman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edition 2 of This Week in Kate's Brain - Living Well/Living Meaningfully]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2012/02/26/edition-2-of-this-week-in-kates-brain-living-wellliving-meaningfully/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-26T01:20:28+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2012/02/26/edition-2-of-this-week-in-kates-brain-living-wellliving-meaningfully</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week my life and the articles I was really thinking about coincided very closely. The item of note for me is I moved all of my belongings into storage for an indeterminate amount of time. I'm spending this next month in Jakarta and I'm unsure exactly that I'll be doing after that. Since my current living situation was coming to a close I figured it made sense not to do anything until April when I return. If nothing else I would save a months rent, more likely I will be happy for the flexibility when I return.</p>

<p>Another reason this was "in Kate's Brain" this week was after a discussion with Christiann. We were discussing retirement and she made the statement that she "didn't think about retirement." This wasn't in the careless way someone might say. To me it was the 30s idea of "do we have to live the traditional life of our parents?"</p>

<h2>How do Happy People Spend Their Money?</h2>

<p>As the economy continues to evolve and change and as people's lifestyles continue to develop traditional values about money and life are changing. This is the premise of <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1817649/how-the-happiest-people-in-the-world-spend-their-money">How the Happiest People in the World Spend Their Money</a>. A review of Laura Vanderkam's book <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/All-Money-World-Happiest-ebook/dp/B005GSZZ6K">All the Money in the World: What the Happiest People Know About Getting and Spending</a>, </em>which I have not read yet (but added to my reading list).</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Is everyone going to follow the "American dream" or will people make different choices and be happier making them?</p></li>
<li><p>Are there non-traditional ways to increase your earnings?</p></li>
<li><p>Is traditional retirement going to go away and are there other ways?</p></li>
</ul>


<p>All topics discussed in the article and from Vanderkam's book. I'm certainly already rethinking these things, as are my friends.</p>

<h2>What is this Life all Worth?</h2>

<p>As the pursuit of things has out weighed the pursuit of satisfaction in life <a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/haque/2011/05/is_a_well_lived_live_worth_anything.html">Is a Well Lived Life Worth Anything</a>? The premise by Umair Haque is today was are in a "Great Stagnation" not just an economic down-turn.  To recover fully there is more at stake that simply fixing the GDP, people will still be not living a life worth living. Many people work on things that they don't find to be meaningful. What if they worked on something meaningful? If you "tapped into their inspiration and imagination and set them to work on stuff that actually mattered?"</p>

<p>The term <a href="http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/194960/eudaemonism?anchor=ref273308">eudaimonia</a> comes from the Greeks and means to live a "meaningfully well-lived life". By all of us striving to do that it would allow switch from "opulence to eudaimonia." Switching will not be instant, but what can an individual do now to live this way? Reading this caused me to put a book on my reading list entitled <a href="http://hbr.org/product/betterness-economics-for-humans/an/11135-PDF-ENG"><em>Betterness: Economics for Humans</em>.</a> Which is summarized as a guide from big to small scale to make things better and "redefine prosperity."</p>

<p>These brief paragraphs hardly scratch the surface of the blog post and I suggest you read it yourself if these ideas seem of interest to you.</p>

<h2>What am I Thinking?</h2>

<p>As I sit on a 14 hour flight to Hong Kong to return to Jakarta I think about where I am in relation to these premises.  Do I spend my money as a happy person does? Is my life meaningful and am I living it well?</p>

<p>I think the answer is "sometimes" or "maybe." Meaning I believe in the work I'm doing now and I have amazing friends. Does that stop me from sometimes spending on things I don't need or that don't contribute to the premise of happiness or meaning? No I doesn't. Does my work take me frequently from friends and family? This does not always lead to happiness, but I would say I'm generally happy. The distance is fortunately in the goal of doing work that is important to me. Sometimes though am I away for a conference or other reason that lacks that meaning? Yes, sometimes when you start traveling most of the time it is hard to slow down, it can be difficult to be home. Once I am home I have a sense of belonging but it is possible sometimes to lose that while I'm away. Hopefully though from this being in my brain this week it can continue to be there are through mindfulness I can continue down the path to further happiness and meaningfulness.</p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in Kate's Brain]]></title>
    <link href="http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2012/02/20/this-week-in-kates-brain/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-20T01:15:31+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://wonderchook.github.com/blog/2012/02/20/this-week-in-kates-brain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking about data is a pretty common topic in my brain, but two particular articles got me thinking this week. Both happened to be from the New York Times.</p>

<p>This first was "<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/19/magazine/shopping-habits.html?_r=1&amp;pagewanted=1&amp;_r=1&amp;hp">How Companies Learn Your Secrets</a>." The introduction to the article was how Target uses statistical analysis to determine which of the company's customers is pregnant so they can target them with coupons. There is even a substory about a father whose daughter received the mailer and came to the store to complain.  It turned out he found out the following week his daughter was indeed pregnant. When a statistician has a training set of data it is amazing what can happen, in this particular case it was women who registered for Target baby registry.  From a privacy perspective it is interested to think about this case, technically Target isn't doing anything wrong but the whole thing seems a bit creepy.</p>

<p>The second article I've really been pondering over this week has been more about how analysis can be used for extreme good. Entitled "<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/19/health/lives-forever-linked-through-kidney-transplant-chain-124.html?_r=3&amp;hp=&amp;pagewanted=all">60 Lives, 30 Kidneys, All Linked</a>." Recently a transplant chain was completed that resulted in 30 people receiving new kidneys. The idea behind the chain is that often there are relatives or friends willing to give a kidney, but are not a match.  The transplant chain allows someone to say "I'll give a kidney as long as the person I want to help is able to receive one."  Organizing such a thing is quite a feat though, for example what if someone backs out after the person they love already receives a kidney? One thing that makes the chain easier is if it is started by someone who is not giving a kidney to a specific person.  The <a href="http://www.kidneyregistry.org/">National Kidney Registry</a> was founded to help create these donation chains. A big step fo them has been convincing the kidney transplant centers to register with the service.</p>

<p>The thinking these articles inspired for me is really about the possibly of data for good and technology for business.  Some perhaps would argue that increasing business with technology is good because it can create jobs, but I think this is very dependent on the circumstances.  Then there are all of the uses for evil, but for me this week there wasn't a particularly poignant article that I read. If you have such an article leave it in my comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
